It's great that we now know how we can send requests and this is a super important part of most web
Artk istek gnderdiimizi bildiimiz iin harika ve elbette ou web uygulamasnn
applications of course.
nemli bir paras.
However, requests don't always succeed,
Bununla birlikte, istekler her zaman baarl olamaz.
you also need to know how you may handle errors
Ayrca, hatalar nasl halledebileceinizi bilmeniz gerekir.
and this is something I want to show you now. Handling errors is super simple with axios,
Ve bu, size hatalar ileme konusunda size gstermek istediim bir ey, Eriim ile sper basittir.
let's say we've fetched the posts incorrectly and of course you can handle errors in the way I'm going
Diyelim ki yanl gnderilmi bir yayn aldk ve elbette hatalar size gstereceim ekilde
to show you
uygulayabilirsiniz.
now for every type of request you send.
imdi gnderdiiniz her tr talepte.
So here in the blog container, let's say we sent the request to postsssss, that's an incorrect
Dolaysyla burada blok konteynerinde, istei yanl olan yaynlara gnderdiimizi dnelim.
URL with that many s'es at the end.
Sonunda o ok ess ile Elswyth'sin.
So what we can now see is that if we reload this, we get an error here but it's unhandled,
imdi grebildiimiz u ki, eer bunu yeniden yklersek burada hata olur, ancak ilenmemi.
we of course want to handle it.
Tabii ki halletmek istiyoruz.
Now since axios uses promises, we don't only have the then method we can chain but we can also add a
Eski U'dan beri. S. zincirle toplayabileceimiz yntemlere sahip olduumuza dair vaatlerde bulunmaz,
second method, simply chain it after
ancak bundan sonra deien ikinci bir yntem de ekleyebiliriz.
then, the catch method, as the names suggests, this catches any errors you get.
Ardndan, gestlerin adlarna gre yakalama yntemi, aldnz hatalar yakalar.
So here, let's for now simply console log that error.If I do that, the request of course still fails
sadece l hava kilitlemek ya da tabii ki isteime bunu yaparsam yine de bakalarnz yanl olduundan baarsz oluyor.
because the URL still is incorrect
yleyse u an iin Konsole
but now the error is handled and here I'm simply printing this with console log.
Ancak imdi hata ileniyor ve burada sadece konsol loguyla yapyorum.
Of course you can do more than logging this here,
Tabii ki bunu burada gnle kaydetmekten daha fazlasn yapabilirsiniz.
you can update your UI,
UI'nizi gncelleyebilirsiniz.
you can update the state to show something went wrong, let me show this. Here we can set an error property,
Durumunuzu, burada bize gsterdiiniz bireyin yanl gittiini gsterebilmek iin gncelleyebilirsiniz, hata
which is set to false initially and in that catch method here, I don't want to log the error, instead I'll
mlkn balangta yanl olarak ayarlayabiliriz ve bu catch ynteminde, hatay stokehole set durumuna kilitlemek ve
set state and I'll set error to true.
hatay ayarlamak istemiyorsanz ya da iki doru.
And now what we can do is we can render something different to the screen. Instead of storing the post
veya balangta bir eyler ters gittiini syleyen yeni bir deiken mesaj yaratmamzdr.
in a constant, I'll create a new variable posts where I'll initially say something went wrong
Ve imdi tek yapabileceimiz, posteri bir sabitte saklamak yerine ekranda farkl bir eyler ileyebiliriz
and let me quickly add some inline styling to center this, so I'll simply add text align center and I'll
Ve merkeziletirme iin hzlca baz satr ii stil eklememe izin verin, bylece sadece metin hizalama merkezi
only overwrite these posts very little if error is not set.
ekleyeceim ve hata kurulmamsa bu yazlar ok az geeceim.
So if this.state.error, if this is not true indicated by the exclamation mark at the beginning. Then I
Bu durum hatas, eer bu doru deilse bataki nlem iareti ile
will then overwrite posts to my array of posts.
gsterilirse, o zaman yaz dizisine yazlanlar yazarm.
So now with that if we save this and center should be a string,
yleyse imdi eer bunu kaydedip Merkezimiz bir ip olmal.
thank you,
Teekkr ederim.
if we save this now, we see something went wrong here because now we have this error.
imdi bunu kaydedersek, burada bir eylerin ters gittiini gryoruz, nk imdi bu hataya sahibiz.
Now if I return to my application and fix posts here to the correct URL, we would see the posts again
imdi bavurusuna dnp buradaki yaynlarm L adresine dzeltirsem, bunun yerine yaynlar tekrar
instead.
grecektim.
So that is a pretty cool way of handling errors and that is something you definitely also need to be
Dolaysyla, hatalar ileme konusunda olduka gzel bir yol budur ve bu da kesinlikle farknda olunmas
aware of.
gereken bir eydir.
Things don't always succeed so you should have a way of catching errors and then doing something with
ler her zaman baarl olamaz, bu nedenle hatalar yakalamann ve onlarla bir eyler yaparak
them, logging them to the console, sending some error log requests to your own server to log the error
konsolda oturum aarak bunlar kendi sunucunuza kendi sunucunuza gndererek hatay kilitlemenizi ve / veya kullancya
and or show something on the UI to allow the user to still continue or to give instructions what the
izin vermek iin UI'da bir ey gstermesini salamann bir yolu olmal halen devam ettirmek veya kullancnn ne
user should do instead.
yapmas gerektiini ynergeler vermek.